http://www.ria.ie/privacy-and-data-protection

Biology and Environment
Proceedings of the Royal Irish Academy: Archaeology, Culture, History, Literature
Humanities and Social Sciences Committees
Coiste Léann na Gaeilge, Litríocht na Gaeilge agus na gCultúr Ceilteach
Ethical, Political, Legal and Philosophical Studies Committee
Historical Studies Committee
Social Sciences Committee
Study of Languages, Literature, Culture and Communication Committee
Login
THE ROYAL IRISH ACADEMY IS IRELAND'S LEADING BODY OF EXPERTS IN THE SCIENCES AND HUMANITIES
The Royal Irish Academy/Acadamh Ríoga na hÉireann champions research. We identify and recognise Ireland’s world class researchers. We support scholarship and promote awareness of how science and the humanities enrich our lives and benefit society. We believe that good research needs to be promoted, sustained and communicated. The Academy is run by a Council of its members. Membership is by election and considered the highest academic honour in Ireland.
Read more about the RIA
Home About the Academy Governance Privacy & Data Protection
About the Academy
Who we are
What We Do
Where We Are
History of the Academy
GovernanceAcademic Board
Privacy and Data Protection
Welcome to the Academy’s data protection, privacy and data retention pages.
The Royal Irish Academy operates in compliance with the Data Protection Acts, GDPR and the Privacy & Electronic Communications Directive 2002/58 EC (to be updated by the forthcoming ePrivacy Regulation) in relation to the collection, use and retention of personal data.  The Royal Irish Academy is the Data Controller of most of the personal data we process.  In a few specific instances we are the Data Processors of personal data.
Our latest Data Protection Policy which will be subject to constant review to ensure currency is available here
Data Protection Terms is available here
Our Web Privacy Statement is here
Our Cookie Policy is available here
Our Ecommerce and Website data privacy statement is available here
Our Notice and Take Down Procedure is available here
Our Data Protection: Personal Data Breach Policy and Procedures for addressing data breaches is available here
Our CCTV Policy is here
Data Protection & Data Retention Statements from Academy departments:
For information on how various sections and Academy projects handle data (personal and otherwise) and accompanying data retention cycles please check out the following links
Accounts
Communications and Public Affairs
Dictionary of Irish Biography
Dictionary of Medieval Latin from Celtic Sources
Digital Repository of Ireland
Documents on Irish Foreign Policy
Financial Donations to the Academy
Foclóir Stairiúil na Gaeilge
Praeger Grants in Natural History
Royal Irish Academy-Royal Society International Exchanges Cost Share
US-Ireland Research Innovation Award
Nowlan Digitisation Grants
Library
ALCID forms
Donations and bequests of books, collections, archives or artefacts
Enquiries
Exhibitions
Financial donations to the Library
Loans and Inter-library loan request and copyright declaration
Mailing list registration form and database
Order forms for digital images/microfilms
Permission to photograph mss etc. using phone/camera etc. form
Permission to to reproduce RIA mss etc. in publications or other media
Reader registration forms
Readers' sign-in register
Records retention schedule
Request forms for photocopies/scans
Check out how we use third-party distribution services
MailChimp
Jotform
Eventbrite
For further information or to make a Subject Access Request or a complaint, please contact the Data Protection Officer, dataprotection@ria.ie or write:
Wayne Aherne, Data Protection Officer, Royal Irish Academy, 19, Dawson Street, Dublin D02 HH58, Ireland.
The Office of the Data Protection Commissioner may be contacted at Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, Co. Laois R32 AP23  www.dataprotection.ie
Stay up to date with the Royal Irish Academy newsletter
Sign up now
page bottom
